GEORGE TSIMIS

Software Engineer

📞 (347) 739-6542 🔞 gt2186@gmail.com 🕜 www.georgetsimis.com

New York, NY

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

08/2022 - Present

Aspen Capital

New York, NY

 Project lead to greatly enhance, and currently maintain, the automated phone system (Twilio API), including testing / error logging, allowing for making payments, saving bank accounts, and configuring autopay. Monthly payments made / revenue collected averages 3K+ / \$5M+

- Project lead for migrating nightly process that updates databases with payment information, from Chase, to AWS utilizing S3, Lambdas, SQS, and SNS. Replaced previous process of stored long SQL procedures resulting in better logging, error handling, and process efficiency
- Maintain / add features to user-facing app, which borrowers (19K+ active with growing adoption) use to make payments, configure autopay, upload / download documents, view loan information / payment history. Monthly payments made / revenue collected averages 11K+ / \$20M+
- Developed and maintain, including writing tests, the API and micro-services written in Java / Spring Boot and Node.js. Add RESTful endpoints that return appropriate data to frontend. Participate in rotational weekly on-call for micro-services. Proficient in IntelliJ IDEA
- Added backend feature, utilizing Intercom API & AWS SNS, that sends two email reminders
 to borrowers that started the process, in user-facing app, of manually linking their bank
 accounts through micro-deposits, to complete the process
- Added feature that allows admins to configure autopay on behalf of borrowers, in internal app, for loans with various statuses (i.e. current, bankruptcy, commercial), requiring different input parameters and backend logic depending on loan status
- Collaborate with teams across the business to understand needs, improve processes, and create realistic plans to complete goals. Participate in software design and architecture discussions. Review team members' pull requests and provide feedback to improve codebase quality

Software Engineer I

02/2022 - 07/2022

LynxDx, Inc.

Ann Arbor, MI (Remote)

- Helped rebuild the Laboratory Information Management System in 3 months from the ground up, resulting in improved performance, scalability, and user experience
- Redesigned all database tables and set up new associations for increased efficiency and performance of database querying
- Added backend and frontend tests allowing the team to confirm new code hasn't affected previous working code

Financial Data Analyst

07/2018 - 07/2021

Moody's Corporation

New York, NY

- Ensured accuracy, consistency, and analytical value of a portfolio of 300+ public and private business entities
- Liaised with senior analysts to resolve queries about financial data used in the ratings process
- Managed and supported an offshore team, that performed data entry, by analyzing their work, making corrections, and providing feedback
- Trained new hires on portfolio management, accounting standards used in the ratings process, and Moody's based software

Mathematics Adjunct Lecturer

08/2016 - 12/2017

City University of New York

New York, NY

- Taught undergraduate courses (approx. 35 students) in elementary algebra, college algebra & trigonometry, precalculus, and calculus
- Created course syllabi and lectures in alignment with CUNY standards to ensure students perform their best on departmental exams
- Designed homework problems of varying difficulty to reinforce concepts learned in class
- Held office hours to address students' concerns and develop study action plans to facilitate a better understanding of difficult concepts



SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 2+ years of professional full stack experience. Previous experience in finance at Moody's Corporation assisting lead analysts in the ratings process, and as a Mathematics Adjunct Lecturer at the City University of New York.

SKILLS

AWS · Axios · CSS3 · Docker · Figma · Git ·

GitHub · HTML5 · Intercom · Java ·

JavaScript · Jest · Jira · Kubernetes ·

MongoDB · Next.js · Node.js · Plaid ·

PostgreSQL · Pulumi · React.js ·

React Testing Library · Spring Boot · SQL ·

Tailwind CSS · Twilio · TypeScript

EDUCATION

App Academy

11/2021

Web development bootcamp with 1000hour curriculum and < 3% acceptance rate

CUNY Queens College

09/2021

Master of Arts in Mathematics

CUNY Queens College

09/2019

Bachelor of Arts in Accounting Minor in Economics

CUNY Queens College

06/2016

Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics (Honors)